MATUZALEM ('MAT') MULLER DOS SANTOS

Los Angeles, CA, US / matmuller.development@gmail.com

GitHub.com/matuzalemmuller / LinkedIn.com/in/matuzalemmuller/ / matuzalemmuller.com

M.Sc. in Automation and Systems engineering and Software Developer. Eager to improve people's lives through technology.

Software developer with +5 years of experience working with technical support management, remote servers maintenance (SSH, Linux), AWS (EC2 and S3), Python programming, and GitLab CI/CD pipelines. I am looking for an opportunity to sharpen my DevOps/cloud infrastructure skills and be part of a collaborative team, building tools and processes to ease development, release, and everyday life.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Santa Catarina (UFSC), Florianópolis, SC, Brazil

Mar 2020 - Feb 2022

M.Sc. in Automation and Systems Engineering

Thesis: BDI Agent-Oriented Programming in Embedded Systems

Published paper: Directions for implementing BDI agents in embedded systems with limited hardware resources

Federal Institute of Santa Catarina (IFSC), São José, SC, Brazil

Mar 2012 - Dec 2019

B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of California Santa Barbara (UCSB), Santa Barbara, CA, USA

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016

Electrical Engineering, non-degree international student, Brazil Scientific Mobility Program (BSMP)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer, ElephantDrive Inc (Los Angeles, CA, US)

Sep 2021 – Present

- Create and maintain GitLab CI/CD pipelines to automate service deployment, build client applications, and run testing routines;
- Design and develop functionalities for managing AWS infrastructure and monitoring alerts;
- Contribute to designing the development roadmap for client applications (mobile, desktop, and NAS) and website, based on previous experience with customer support and knowledge of customer expectations/needs;
- Coordinate software releases with strategic partners and publish new software versions to App Stores.

Technical Specialist, ElephantDrive Inc (Florianópolis, SC, Brazil - remote)

Jan 2018 - Aug 2021

- Maintained remote infrastructure used for testing and building client applications, with Windows, Linux, and NAS servers;
- Performed manual and automated testing and quality assurance tasks for websites and client applications on Windows, macOS, Ubuntu, and NAS. Tests mainly were manual, but also programmed tests for the websites using the Selenium package for Java;
- Contributed to designing the development roadmap for client applications (mobile, desktop, and NAS) and website, based on experience with customer support and knowledge of customer expectations/needs;
- Provided support level 2 worldwide: +4300 tickets resolved with 92% "Good" satisfaction rate in the ticketing platform.

Market Development Consultant, ElephantDrive Inc (Florianópolis, SC, Brazil - remote)

Jun 2016 - Jan 2018

- Assisted in contract negotiations for a partnership with a Brazilian company and establishing a product brand in Brazil;
- Updated internal technical documentation on Confluence and external documentation on Help Desk;
- Provided support levels 1 and 2 in Brazil: +3000 tickets resolved with 95% "Good" satisfaction rate in the ticketing platform.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Dummy Files Generator (Python + PyQt): Desktop application that generates dummy files with random content. https://bit.ly/3rvJzzm **Frevo** (Python + PyQt): Run configurable commands from the Mac top bar. https://bit.ly/3B7a69p

Embedded-BDI (C++ / Master's Thesis): Framework to program BDI agents for embedded systems. https://bit.ly/3ovhxlN

SKILLS

Advanced: Python, Linux (+10 years of daily usage and +5 years of server maintenance), SSH, Git, Bash, Level 2 support management.

Intermediate: C/C++, Docker, GitLab CI, GitHub Actions, LaTeX, Jira, Networking, AWS, GCP, OCI, Project Management.

Basic: MATLAB, Java, MySQL, Jenkins, Grafana, Prometheus, Kubernetes, Terraform.

Language: native Portuguese, fluent English.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Honors: BSMP, selected among best students in Brazil for a full scholarship to study abroad, funded by the Brazilian government.

Certificate: Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations 2021 Associate. Feb 2022.

Certificate: GitLab Certified Associate. Jan 2022.

Certificate: Mutirão DevOps. Dec 2021. 7 months long DevOps training with classes presenting topics such as Kubernetes and CI/CD.

Certificate: Specialization: AWS Fundamentals. AWS. 4 Courses. Aug 2020.

Certificate: Technical Support Fundamentals. Google. Jul 2020.